Let us now understand the Scrollspy and
接下来就让我们学习一下
Affix plug-ins that are available within Bootstrap.
Bootstrap 的滚动监听 和附加导航插件吧
The Scrollspy plug-in is applied to a nav element,
滚动监听插件常常被应用在导航上
such that as you scroll your web page,
从而当你滚动页面时
whatever is currently visible on the screen
能够在导航元素中实时地高亮
will be highlighted in the nav page.
你当前页面的部分
So that the corresponding nav element In the nav bar, or
这样一来 你就能大概地掌握
in the nav item that you display, would be highlighted on the screen.
你当前阅览的部分 在页面所有内容中的相对位置
It is best for us to go and
为使你更清楚滚动监听的功用
look at an example to understand this behavior before we come back and
我们先来看一个栗子吧
examine how we would implement the Scrollspy and the Affix plugin.
至于其具体实现 我们之后会说
These two go together in some sense, so
顺带一提 在某种意义上 滚动监听和附加导航是同心一体的
that's the reason why I'm covering the two together.
这也是为什么我把 它们放在一起来教你们
To understand these two plugins, let's go to our bootstrap web page itself.
为理解这两个插件 让我们去 Bootstrap 的官网看看吧
Getbootstrap.com and
也就是 getbootstrap.com
I am right now under the Javascript part of the bootstrap web page.
而我现在这个页面 则是其中的 JavaScript 部分
You can see that on the right side, we have a nav bar here.
你可以看到右边这里 有一个导航栏
This must have been implemented using nav-pills.
这些应该是用 nav-pills 实现的
So as you scroll, you can see that the nav
然后当你滚动页面时
bar on the right side, scrolls up.
你可以看到右边这个导航栏 会随着往上滚动
As you scroll the page, but when you hit the top,
然后当这个导航栏"撞"到 页面的顶部时
notice the subtle change in the behavior.
你会发现它发生了些微的改变
When the scroll goes up to a certain point, the nav bar suddenly
比如说它会突然跳到某个位置
jumps up and then gets itself fixed to a location.
并从此固定在那里
As you scroll now you can see that the item that you're
然后当你继续滚动页面时
viewing on the webpage gets highlighted in the nav items there.
你可以发现与你当前阅览的部分 相对应的导航栏的部分被高亮了出来
And as you keep scrolling, the individual
然后当你继续滚动时
items get highlighted in the nav bar there.
相应的,分得更细的导航元素 又会相应地被高亮
So scrolling more quickly,
即使你很快地滚动页面
you can see that at every single point the corresponding item in
在每一个时间点上 通过改变颜色
the nav is being highlighted by changing its color on the right side.
相应的导航元素都会被高亮出来
Scrolling further you can see that behavior again one more time.
而如果你向回滚动
When you scroll back, you will see that the plugin again jumps back and
并一直滚动到页面顶部时
then starts scrolling back with the page at some point.
你能看到刚刚的行为 被"倒带"了一遍
Now, these two behaviors are implemented using the Scrollspy and Affix plugins.
这种效果就是用 滚动监听和附加导航实现的
The Scrollspy plugin tracks the current
其中滚动监听允许我们获得
scroll position of the web page, and then reflects that
当前我们网页的位置并通过
by highlighting the appropriate nav item in the nav element there.
高亮相应的导航元素来反馈
The Affix plug-in enables your nav element to move with the scroll
而附加导航则允许你让你的 导航元素实现一定的定位
up to a certain point and when it reaches a certain point,
比如当页面滚动到特定的地方时
then the Affix plugin will fix the position.
附加导航插件可以将你的 导航元素固定在页面的某个部分
This is done by changing the position CSS property of
这是通过改变相应元素的 CSS 的 position 属性来实现的
that element from relative to fixed position.
具体而言 就是把 position 从 relative 换成 fixed
The Scrollspy plugin is enabled as follows.
为激活滚动监听插件
We need to apply certain data attributes to
我们需要对网页中我们想要 追踪的那个元素
an element of the webpage which we want to track.
设置特定的 data 属性
Now Scrollspy expects that this element of the web page
由于滚动监听要求 其作用的元素的
will have a position that's relative.
position 属性为 relative
Now this is easiest done by assigning this to the body
所以一般而言最简单的做法就是
element of our web page, our body tag of our web page,
对 body 标签应用滚动监听
because the body tag by default gets the position [INAUDIBLE].
因为 body 标签的 position 属性 默认就是 [relative]
So which means that the Scrollspy will be able to track the scroll position of
如果你确实对 body 标签 应用了滚动监听的话
the inner elements inside the body tag.
那么它就会监听 body 标签里面 那些内容相对页面的方位
To do that, we are going to assign to the body
具体的实现亦不复杂
a data spy attribute with scroll.
只需对 body 设置 data-spy="scroll" 即可
And then I gave the data target pointing to the ID of
注意到我还设置了 data-target="#myScrollspy"
the scroll nav element that we're going to introduce later.
其中 myScrollspy 正是我们接下来 要实现的导航元素的 id
So in this example, I am giving the nav element a an ID as myScrollspy.
你可以看到在这个栗子里 我就对一个 nav 标签设置了这个 id
And so that’s why I’m giving you the data target.
然后你可以看到我还对 body
And the data offset is 200, which means that the actual tracking of the scroll
设置了 data-offset="200" 这意味着对滚动的监听将会从
position begins 200 pixels from the top.
页面顶部往下 200 像素的位置开始
So this is the offset that we give,
这是因为在我们这个网页里
essentially to avoid tracking the upper 200 pixels.
我们在它的顶部放了 大概有 200 像素高的
Recall that when you look at your web page,
一个 Jumbotron【超大屏幕】
the top part of the web page contains the jumbotron.
为使效果更好 我们希望
We are not going to track the part of the jumbotron, we want to track the rest of
在超大屏幕之后才开始
our content of the webpage, the actual content in our webpage.
进行剩余部分的滚动监听
So that's why I have given it a data offset of 200.
这就是为什么我设置了 data-offset="200"
Now, to apply the Scrollspy itself,
然后在这个栗子里 我们用了一个 nav 标签
I need to introduce a nav element into my webpage.
来充当滚动监听的本体
To this nav element, I introduce the property classes, but, in particular,
对这个 nav 标签 我除了对其设置 相应的定制其外观的类以外
I give it an id, which is the same as the ID that I use
我还将它的 id 设置为了
in the data target in my body tag.
上面 body 标签里面的 data-target 属性的值
Now inside that, we will use the UL class with the nav and
然后在 nav 标签里面 我用了一个设置了
in this example I am using the nav-pills and nav-stacked classes there.
class="nav nav-pills nav-stacked" 的 ul 标签
So this will create the nav element as a nav-pills
这将会是一个胶囊式的导航元素
element with the pills stacked vertically, one on top of the other.
而且它将会竖直堆叠
Now, inside here, of course, I have the list Items here each corresponding to
然后在 ul 里面自然就是 li 了
the various content rows that I have in my webpage.
它们对应着页面的 各个不同的行
For each of those rows I need to give the corresponding id
注意我会对这些行 都设置一个相应的 id
that I am using in the href attribute for these a tags here.
然后在这里这些 li 标签中 我都放了一个 a 标签
Let us now see this Scrollspy in action on our webpage.
这些 a 标签的 href 属性的值 自然就是对应行的 id 了
So I have used this inside my aboutus.html page.
回到我们的 aboutus.html 网页
So you can see that I have the nav element on the right side,
你可以看到右边这里有一个
which is a nav-pills stacked.
堆叠在一起的胶囊式导航元素
So as I scroll the page, you can see that the nav element scrolls with it.
然后当我滚动页面时 你能看到这个导航会随之滚动
I’m also using the affix here, so
不过由于我用了附加导航
I'm going to explain the affix part a little bit later.
所以你可以看到它到一定位置后 就会一直固定在某个地方
So as you scroll, as our row comes into our view there,
然后当你继续滚动时
the corresponding item Is being highlighted in my nav element.
你可以看到页面显示的内容 所对应的导航元素将被高亮出来
So I can see that currently, I'm viewing the History.
比如我现在看的是 Our History
So as I scroll to see the Corporate, that will be highlighted.
右边写着 Our History 的导航元素 就被高亮了出来
And then as I scroll past, and
然后当我继续向下滚动时
then the Facts & Figures come up, that item will be highlighted in the nav page.
你可以看到右边的 被高亮出来的导航元素
Scrolling backwards, you see the same behavior one more time.
也随着页面显示内容的改变 而相对应地改变着
Now let's look at how the affix part of it works.
接下来让我们看看 附加导航的具体用法
So for the affix plugin to work, you see that for the ul class I have given it
为使附加导航插件切实地运作 在这个栗子里 我对 ul 标签
the data spy attribute as affix and then I set the data-offset-top as 400.
设置了 data-spy="affix" 和 data-offset-top="400"
This means that as the scrolling happens,
这意味着当我滚动页面时
when my webpage scrolls past the 400 pixel mark from the top,
如果我从顶部算起 滚动了 400 像素的话
up to that point my nav element will scroll together with the webpage.
那么附加导航插件将会运作
At that point, what happens is that the affix plugin
从而将 ul 标签中的
will change the class given to
position 这项属性
this ul from affix top to the affix class there.
从 relative 变成 fixed
Now, when the change happens, the position CSS property of this
这是通过更改 ul 标签的
nav element will be changed from position relative to position fixed.
CSS 属性实现的
So at that point this nav element gets fixed
这项修改将会使这个 ul 标签
on the webpage to a specific location.
一直固定在页面的某个特定位置
Now, when does that fixing get triggered?
总而言之
That is specified by the data-offset-top attribute that I am giving here.
data-offset-top 这项属性的值 就代表着附加导航激活的位置
And then I am specifying the position is 400, so
在这个栗子里我设置了 400
when you scroll past the 400 pixel mark, at that point that nav element gets fixed.
就意味着从顶部向下滚动 400 像素后 附加导航插件就会运作
How do you decide this?
那么怎么决定这个值呢 ?
That you will have to look at the structure of your webpage and then decide
一般来说都是视情况而定的
at what point it is appropriate to fix that nav element into a given position.
它取决于你页面的结构
So, again, reviewing, we see that the Affix plugin is triggered by
那么复习一下
using the data-spy in the affix, and
附加导航需要用 data-spy="affix" 来激活
the data-offset-top with 400 applied to the ul class that we saw.
然后需要用 data-offset-top来定制 在这个栗子里则是设置了 400
In addition, inside my style start CSS file I am going to add
特别的 我还将在我们 自己的 CSS 文件中加进一些代码 :
an affix class with the property as top fixed to 100 pixels.
.affix  top: 100px;
What this means is that my nav element is going to
这意味着当附加导航插件运作后
be fixed from the top position of the webpage, 200 pixels.
我们的导航元素将会固定在
So when I change the position property to position fixed,
离我们网页页面顶部
the location is 100 pixels from the top of the webpage.
100 像素的位置上
Going back to our webpage, you see that as I scroll
回到我们的网页 你可以看到 当我一开始滚动我们的网页时
the webpage my nav element scrolls with it.
导航元素会随之滚动
But at a certain point, the nav element gets fixed there, so
不过当滚动到一定地方后
you can see the triggering of the fixing of the nav element there.
你可以看到导航元素会 突然被固定到页面的某个位置
That nav element now is fixed at 100 pixels from the top of the webpage there,
具体而言 就是离页面顶部 100 像素的地方
and subsequently will remain fixed at that position when I scroll.
然后接下来无论我滚动多少 导航元素都会一直固定在那里
When I scroll back again, when I reach the 400 pixel mark,
然后如果我往回滚动的话 如果过了 400 像素那条线
then the affix class will be removed and
附加导航的效果就会被移除
affix top class will be fixed, will be given to this nav element.
从而导航元素的表现
And then the position is changed to relative at that point, so
将会恢复如初
that's why the nav element, again, scrolls with the web page.
具体而言就是 position 属性的值 从 fixed 变回了 relative
This completes our discussion on the Affix plugin.
以上 我们完成了 对附加导航的讨论与学习
Now, in the next exercise,
在下一个练习里
we're going to make use of the accordion, the Scrollspy and Affix, and
我们将会同时应用 折叠, 滚动监听和附加导航
then apply each to the aboutus.html page that we have been designing so far.
我们将会在 aboutus.html 中 应用这些我们刚学过的东西
We're going to enclose the corporate leadership content into an accordion and
我们将会把 corporate leadership 这一块封装进折叠里面
we're gonna add another nav element to the right hand side
然后正如我们刚刚看到的
to track the position of the scroll of our webpage.
我们将会在页面右边 实现一个导航元素
So we're going to make use of the Scrollspy for this purpose.
我们将会对这个导航元素
And then we're going to that Scrollspy nav element,
同时应用滚动监听和附加导航 从而让这个导航元素
we're gonna apply the Affix plugin to fix the position when we scroll the webpage.
实现刚刚我们看到的效果 【翻译 - Carefree0910】